an act of omission, of shallowness, the sin of anger, the sin of self-pity, trying to be a people-pleaser, a lack of courage. Adam I is built by building on your strengths. Adam II is built by fighting your weaknesses. You go into yourself, you find the sin which you've committed over and again through your life, your signature sin out of which the others emerge, and you fight that sin and you wrestle with that sin, and out of that wrestling, that suffering, then a depth of character is constructed. And we're often not taught to recognize the sin in ourselves, in that we're not taught in this culture how to wrestle with it, how to confront it, and how to combat it. We live in a culture with an Adam I mentality where we're inarticulate about Adam II. Finally, Reinhold Niebuhr summed up the confrontation, the fully lived Adam I and Adam II life, this way: "Nothing that is worth doing can be achieved in our lifetime; therefore we must be saved by hope. Nothing which is true or beautiful or good makes complete sense in any immediate context of history; therefore we must be saved by faith. Nothing we do, however virtuous, can be accomplished alone; therefore we must be saved by love. No virtuous act is quite as virtuous from the standpoint of our friend or foe as from our own standpoint. Therefore we must be saved by that final form of love, which is forgiveness.” Thanks. (Applause)
un acto de omisión, de superficialidad, el pecado de la ira, de la autocompasión, un intento de complacer a la gente, una falta de coraje. Adán 1 se construye al construir tus fortalezas. Adán 2 se construye superando debilidades. Mira hacia tu interior, encuentra el pecado que hayas cometido una y otra vez a lo largo de tu vida, tu pecado típico del cual surgen otros pecados, y pelea y lucha contra ese pecado, y de esa lucha, de ese sufrimiento se construye la profundidad de carácter. Y generalmente no se nos enseña a reconocer el pecado en nosotros mismos, nuestra cultura no nos enseña a luchar contra él, cómo enfrentarlo, y cómo combatirlo. Vivimos en una cultura con una mentalidad de Adán 1 en donde no podemos hacer nada sobre Adán 2. Finalmente, Reinhold Niebuhr resumió la confrontación, la vida al máximo de Adán 1 y Adán 2, de la siguiente manera: "Nada que valga la pena hacer se puede lograr en toda una vida; por lo cual nos debe salvar la esperanza. Nada que sea verdad o bello o bueno tiene sentido en el contexto inmediato de la historia; por lo tanto nos debe salvar la fe. Nada de lo que hagamos, sin importar cuán virtuoso sea, se logra solo; por lo tanto, nos debe salvar el amor. Ningún acto virtuoso es tan virtuoso desde el punto de vista de nuestro amigo o enemigo como lo es desde el nuestro. Por lo tanto, nos debe salvar esa forma final de amor, que es el perdón". Muchas gracias. (Aplausos)